The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Thirtieth Episode
The Phantom Kite
How delightful!
My crown has disappeared!
Quick, search for it! Find it!
The phantom thief Gilbert?
Yes... Yes, yes! He is a strange
thief who only targets crowns.
He has never been
caught or seen by anyone.
All that is known is that he is
incredibly agile and strong!
Majesty, it seems that Gilbert
has been seen around here.
My God, how I like Gilbert!
I can't wait to see him!
- But I say... Sapphire!
- Yes, mother...
They say he appeared suddenly
in the town next to ours.
Did he steal some crowns there too?
We don't know!
He's so fast...
...that you can never know
where and when he arrives.
It's said that he wants to remain a thief
until he has stolen 10 crowns!
What a strange fellow!
Then he could also steal
my father and mother's crown!
That would be terrible!
If they steal it from you,
you can put on another one.
No, we can't. This is part
of the Silverland treasure.
It was made
by a great master.
Really? Looking at it, it seems
like just an ordinary crown.
Anyway, you'll have to be
very careful.
You know well that,
if they were to steal the crown from you,
you would fall into disgrace!
I know, but I'll try to be
very careful.
How I love
watching the parades!
That's the phantom thief Gilbert!
Someone shoot down that kite!
Now I'll bring you down!
Hey! Give us back the crown!
Tink, watch out!
Help!
Thank you!
Nylon had warned you
that Gilbert would come...
...and you let the crown
be stolen so easily!
It's shameful! Have you
forgotten that the crown...
...is the precious
treasure of Silverland?
How could I have imagined that
he would come right from the sky?
It means that, for the
moment, I'll put on another one.
For the moment?!
Do you perhaps hope the stolen
crown will return on its own?
But we don't even
know where it ended up?!
I will search for it myself
and I will certainly find it!
- Sapphire!
- Mother, if I don't do this,
these two people
will never stop talking!
How brave you are,
Princess Sapphire!
How long do you think it will take you
to find it?
It would be a real shame
if it took three years!
- Three days.
- Three days?!
I will get it back in three days.
Are you satisfied?
Certainly, Princess Sapphire!
We know how brave you are.
It's wonderful to hear you say
...that you will manage to get
the crown back in three days.
But, to actually do it,
how long do you think it will take you?
I can't wait for
the fourth day to come!
You were good! But will you manage
to get it back in only three days?
Besides, the thief is a strange
fellow, who flies on a kite.
- It's impossible to catch him!
- Then I will fly too.
What?! You intend to fly?!
Yes! Look!
This is a poster
for the circus that has arrived in town.
Yes! I'll go there and have them
teach me some acrobatics.
Stop joking, please!
You are a Princess!
- Something like acrobatics...!
- Well then, Doctor Uranaru,
can you teach me
another way to fly?
Actually, I'll think about it.
No, no, no... There's no time.
I promised to do it in three days.
I know, but there's nothing
that can be done now.
Listen!
They say that this boy, Trot,
...is able to fly
on a kite.
Doctor Uranaru,
please investigate,
into what Trot was doing
when the crown was stolen.
I'll have to play detective too...
Gilbert's true identity
could be that of Trot.
Ah, I see!
And one more thing: we must
succeed in luring Gilbert.
- Lure him?!
- Yes.
Oh, yes, yes! Yes, yes, I understand!
And now, Uranaru,
have the people warned immediately!
This way, Gilbert will arrive!
You are truly clever!
What?! They say that the night after tomorrow
there will be another military parade.
Really?! Did they
have to hold it at night?
It is said that the crown that was
stolen during yesterday's parade...
...is a fake crown, created
to deceive the thief Gilbert.
I told you so!
It wasn't possible...
...that the King would let
a crown be stolen so easily.
A fake crown...
Trot!
- Are you ready? It's your turn next! Hurry up!
- Yes, alright!
- Princess Sapphire!
- Uranaru, well?
It seems that Trot was performing
his acrobatics...
...while they were stealing the crown!
There are many witnesses.
I see.
Then he is not Gilbert.
I have informed the population
about the military parade.
Alright, thank you!
Then I'll go to the circus right away.
...and have them teach me
how to fly on a kite!
Hey, Princess Sapphire!
Where are you going?
We only have two days left!
- Bravo!
- Good!
And now, for you, a master
of kite flying!
Trot will show you, to start with,
"Big wave and small wave"!
The next act
will be "Revolution"!
And now pay attention!
Trot will draw for you
a beautiful picture in the sky!
Bravo! Bravo!
- You're the best!
- Bravo!
Bravo! He doesn't even seem
like a human being!
Are you the one who would like
to learn how to fly on a kite?
Yes! Please, make me
your pupil!
He showed no sign of surprise
at seeing me...
As I thought,
it isn't Gilbert.
You say that, but it's very different
from riding a horse.
Only those who are very brave, quick
and skilled can learn to fly.
Fine! Then it seems made
just for me,
because I am brave,
quick and skilled...
...and I'm also strong,
I'm telling you! So, I can!
These hands are white and delicate
like those of a girl!
To fly a kite
you need strong hands!
You're saying something rude!
They are thin, but they are strong
Alright then, I'll give you
a test. Come with me.
First of all, try up here.
Oh, but it's Prince Sapphire!
I wonder why he's here...!
What could he possibly have come here for?
And what is he doing with Trot?!
- Do you think you're capable?
- I'll try.
- How did it go?
- Well, pretty well.
The next one is that! Look!
- Now you try it.
- Do I really have to?
Of course!
Not like that! You have to let yourself go!
- Trot, the boss is calling you!
- Yes, I'm going!
I'll be right back. In the
meantime, you practice.
I'll rest while he's away.
Who is it? Scoundrel, show yourself!
Show yourself!
Here I am! I'm sorry
for making you wait.
But what are you doing?
Aren't you practicing?
I didn't have time to do
it. They tried to kill me.
Suddenly, someone
threw knives at me.
- Why are you laughing?
- If you can't overcome
...a thing like that, you'll
never be able to fly on a kite!
So the knives
didn't hit their mark, huh?
Ah, here they are!
I missed the shot.
Yes! And that thing,
you have to change it for a bigger one!
If something like that falls
on your head, you die immediately.
But why do you want to learn
to fly on a kite?
I have a reason and I have to learn
by tomorrow night.
Alright, I'll be able to teach you
What is important
in kite flying...
...is arm strength
and a sense of balance.
Your left hand
is too weak.
Stand up, now,
and try again! Come on, get up
Stand up!
If you don't want to fall, keep the
same strength in both hands!
Hold on, otherwise
you won't make it by tomorrow!
I finally learned
how to fly on a kite!
Tonight will be
the big moment!
He's so good!
He learned in just one day!
- Trot, do you know who that is?
- No. Who is it?
It's Sapphire,
the Prince of this country!
What are you saying?!
Are you sure, brother?
Yes, absolutely sure.
When I went to steal
the crown, I saw him.
No one, so far, has ever
known that you and I are Gilbert.
He, however, might find out.
He used a fake crown and now he's
organizing another military parade.
What could he have in mind?
His goal might be
to lure us into a trap.
But I will succeed in stealing
the true crown of Silverland!
And now the kite-flying
master...
...will fight
against his pupil!
Return to the castle
and wait for the phantom thief.
Trot! Trot!
That’s Gilbert!
- Really?
- No, it’s Sapphire!
Princess!
- Oh, my God!
- Sapphire!
She’s safe! She’s safe!
- Are you alright, Sapphire?
- Yes, everything is fine, Tink.
Princess, the time you
yourself set will soon arrive!
Yes, Uranaru, I know.
Sapphire, you have something
stuck to your back.
- It’s a letter!
- Read it!
"You dared to make me steal
the false crown,
but tonight I will steal the true one.
Signed:
the phantom thief Gilbert."
It’s from Gilbert! Damn him!
I’ve caught you in a trap and we’ll see
who manages to win this time!
Tonight there will be
the military parade.
How can Gilbert be avoided
if he comes down from the sky?
Let’s see...
Oh yes, I’ve got it!
It's very easy to fly!
We will be able to fly...
...if we fill that bag
with gas! - Yes!
Will you be able to get the crown back?
The moment has arrived.
Hey! Something strange
is descending from the sky!
I don't know what it is, but I'm
telling you to be on your guard!
Help! Help!
There it is! There it
is! It's coming! Hit it!
The crown is mine!
Damn you, Gilbert!
Damn it!
This is luminous paint!
Gilbert, on guard!
If you lose your balance,
you will fall, Sapphire!
Tell me, how do you know
my name?
- Damn it!
- That crown is fake!
- What?!
- I used it to catch you!
"Revolution"!
Here I am!
But how?! You are Trot!
Sapphire, you are admirable.
You have beaten me!
Do with me what you will!
Why on earth did you do
such a thing?
Sapphire, I will reveal
Gilbert's identity to you!
There is another Trot?!
But it's not possible!
Stop it, brother!
We have been defeated!
Brother?!
Now you know: we are twins!
One plays the part of Gilbert
and the other provides the alibis.
Look,
this is my great invention:
a flying basket
filled with gas!
I want to catch
the phantom thief Gilbert!
Yes! Yes! We've caught him!
Curse it!
Brother, we'd better surrender!
They are superior to us!
Sapphire caught Gilbert!
Admirable! Admirable!
Here, father, this is the real one.
Thank you.
I am the guilty one,
so forgive my brother.
It’s not true!
I am the only one to blame!
It's him you must forgive!
I won't forgive either of them!
Tell me one thing:
why do you only steal crowns?
Is there perhaps a specific reason?
In the past, my father was
in the service of a King, as a soldier.
One day, by pure chance
he dropped the King's crown.
He was imprisoned
and then executed as punishment.
I don't know how precious
that crown was,
but a man's life
is certainly more precious.
For us, our father was
the most precious thing in the world.
I understand
Your Majesty, they have come
to take Gilbert!
I was the one who captured him,
so I will punish him!
He ran away!
Gilbert ran away!
Sapphire!
Gilbert escaped! Catch him!
No matter how precious a crown is,
it is nothing
compared to the life of a man.
I can understand Gilbert's feelings
perfectly well.
And I can understand yours, Sapphire.
Believe me.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP